<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfslcdg" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfslcdg</compoundname>
    <title>CFS Limit Checker Deployment Guide</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>The first step in deploying the LC application is to size and construct default WDT and ADT tables. LC requires these default table images to be on the filesystem when the application is started or it will fail to load. These files are required even if using the Critical Data Store (CDS) since LC will fall back to these table images if a table restore from CDS fails (which will happen during a power-on reset). Where LC will look to find these files is dictated by the configuration parameters <ref refid="lc__platform__cfg_8h_1afd0c204981f98d8aae45e76f736bc821" kindref="member">LC_WDT_FILENAME</ref> and <ref refid="lc__platform__cfg_8h_1a3062af572967bd4fde7cfda87f0d8d16" kindref="member">LC_ADT_FILENAME</ref>.</para><para>The size of the WDT and ADT tables is dictated by the configuration parameters <ref refid="lc__platform__cfg_8h_1a3b43c5fab123709355610bb6382804d3" kindref="member">LC_MAX_WATCHPOINTS</ref> and <ref refid="lc__platform__cfg_8h_1ab49788ed10c3f7f4aaaa876a48b49ba3" kindref="member">LC_MAX_ACTIONPOINTS</ref>. The total size of either table should not exceed the cFE size limit for a single buffered table set by the #CFE_TBL_MAX_SNGL_TABLE_SIZE parameter. When considering how many watchpoints and actionpoints are needed, keep in mind the the entire WDT is sequentially searched whenever a message that may contain watchpoints is received. Likewise the entire ADT will be processed whenever a <ref refid="lc__msgids_8h_1a156d2d4b7fa00933aa4f34253f8dfe74" kindref="member">LC_SAMPLE_AP_MID</ref> message is recieved. While it is desirable to leave unused entries in both tables for later updates, large tables will increase search time which may be undesirable depending on the telemetry and actionpoint sample rates required. LC defines the performance ID <ref refid="lc__perfids_8h_1ad8121b157e682f69e643e17033d36e2c" kindref="member">LC_WDT_SEARCH_PERF_ID</ref> that can be used to monitor WDT search time. There is not currently a performance ID for ADT processing since the actionpoint sample cycle is not dependent on telemetry rates but set by the configuration of the scheduler (SCH) application.</para><para>Example source code for these tables sized to the default number of watchpoints and actionpoints are provided in the files lc_def_wdt.c and lc_def_adt.c.</para><para>LC requires a message with the message ID <ref refid="lc__msgids_8h_1a156d2d4b7fa00933aa4f34253f8dfe74" kindref="member">LC_SAMPLE_AP_MID</ref> to sample actionpoints. The CFS scheduler application (SCH) needs to be configured to provide this trigger message at the desired frequency for actionpoint processing to occur.</para><para>The function /LC_ExecuteRTS in the file lc_custom.c needs to be reviewed for any modifications that may be needed to properly initiate RTS responses to actionpoint failures. This function uses a local declaration of an example stored commanding (SC) message structure which was done to allow LC to be compiled independent of any other external application&apos;s data structures. A mission may choose to remove this and use a message structure declared outside LC instead. This also applies to the <ref refid="lc__mission__cfg_8h_1a15d094fa2859f665e373526e3419d8b4" kindref="member">LC_RTS_REQ_MID</ref> and <ref refid="lc__mission__cfg_8h_1afe6f027641a94befc5992e27ee8ecf3e" kindref="member">LC_RTS_REQ_CC</ref> constants in <ref refid="lc__mission__cfg_8h" kindref="compound">lc_mission_cfg.h</ref>.</para><para>If custom functions are to be used, the function /LC_CustomFunction in the file lc_custom.c needs to modified appropriately (see <ref refid="cfslcfaqs" kindref="compound">CFS Limit Checker Frequently Asked Questions</ref>).</para><para>In the <ref refid="lc__platform__cfg_8h" kindref="compound">lc_platform_cfg.h</ref> file, there are configuration parameters that control use of the Critical Data Store (CDS) and the LC operation mode on application initialization. The default case is not to use the CDS and to set the application state to <ref refid="lc__msgdefs_8h_1a3fd2c719b6359d46e31e4726cb3c72d1" kindref="member">LC_STATE_DISABLED</ref>.</para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfslccmds" kindref="compound">CFS Limit Checker Commands</ref> <linebreak/>
 Prev: <ref refid="cfslcreq" kindref="compound">CFS Limit Checker Requirements</ref> </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
