<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfslcovr" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfslcovr</compoundname>
    <title>CFS Limit Checker Overview</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>The CFS Limit Checker (LC) application monitors telemetry data points in the flight system and compares the values against predefined threshold limits. When a threshold condition is encountered, an event message is issued and a Relative Time Sequence (RTS) command script may be initiated to respond to the threshold violation.</para><para>LC is a table driven application. Monitoring and response configuration data is stored in definition tables that can be updated by the ground operators, while statistics on threshold violations are stored in dump-only results tables and summarized in housekeeping data.</para><para>When processing beyond the standard comparison operators is needed, LC supports the use of custom evaluation functions that can be modified by a software patch or application update.</para><sect1 id="cfslcovr_1LC">
<title>Design Overview</title>
<para><verbatim>  The LC design is built around two fundamental constructs. The Watchpoint and the 
  Actionpoint.

  A Watchpoint defines a comparison between a piece of telemetry data and a pre-defined 
  constant. Watchpoints are defined in the Watchpoint Definition Table (WDT). Statistics 
  on watchpoint evaluations are stored in the Watchpoint Results Table (WRT)
  (see \ref cfslctbl). Watchpoints are evaluated whenever a message containing the 
</verbatim> telemetry point is received over the software bus by LC. <verbatim>An Actionpoint defines the response LC will take based upon the current state of one 
or more watchpoints. Actionpoints are defined in the Actionpoint Definition Table (ADT). 
Statistics on actionpoint evaluations are stored in the Actionpoint Results Table (ART)
</verbatim> (see <ref refid="cfslctbl" kindref="compound">CFS Limit Checker Table Definitions</ref>). Actionpoints are evaluated whenever LC receives a message with the <ref refid="lc__msgids_8h_1a156d2d4b7fa00933aa4f34253f8dfe74" kindref="member">LC_SAMPLE_AP_MID</ref> message ID. This is not a ground command but an internal message that will normally come from the CFS scheduler (SCH) application.</para><para><image type="html" name="LC_Context.png">LC Context Diagram</image>
 <linebreak/>
</para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfslcopr" kindref="compound">CFS Limit Checker Operation</ref> <linebreak/>
 Prev: <ref refid="cfslcintro" kindref="compound">CFS Limit Checker Introduction</ref> </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
