<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfetimeugconfig" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfetimeugconfig</compoundname>
    <title>Time Configuration</title>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugformsel">Time Format Selection</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugfaketone">Enabling Fake Tone Signal</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugtoneorder">Selecting Tone and Data Ordering</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugtonewindow">Specifying Tone and Data Window</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugserver">Specifying Time Server/Client</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugvirtualmet">Virtual MET</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugsource">Specifying Time Source</innerpage>
    <innerpage refid="cfetimeugsignal">Specifying Time Signal</innerpage>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>All configurations of TIME require a local processor source for a 1Hz interrupt and access to a local clock with a resolution fine enough that it can be used to measure short periods of elapsed time. The local interrupt is used to wake-up TIME at a regular interval for the purpose of verifying that the tone is being received. The local clock is used to measure time since the tone and to provide coarse verification that the tone is occurring at approximately one second intervals. The presumption is that the tone is the most accurate timer in the system and, within reason, is to be trusted. Note that nothing precludes the use of the MET as the local clock, assuming the MET is both local and provides sub-second data. However, the tone must not be used as the source for the local 1Hz interrupt.</para><para>Consider the following brief description of three hypothetical hardware configurations. These sample systems may be used as reference examples to help clarify the descriptions of the various TIME configuration selections.</para><para>In the first system, there is no MET timer and therefore no tone signal. The MET is a count of the number of &quot;fake&quot; tones generated by TIME software. There is no validation performed regarding the quality of time data. This hardware configuration is a common lab environment using COTS equipment.</para><para>In the second system, the MET timer is a hardware register that is directly accessible by TIME. When MET seconds increment, a processor interrupt signals the tone. Upon detecting the tone, TIME can read the MET to establish the time at the tone. To verify that the tone is valid, TIME need only validate that this tone signal occurred approximately one second after the previous tone signal (as measured with the local clock).</para><para>In the third system, the MET is located on hardware connected via spacewire. When MET seconds increment, a spacewire time tick triggers a local processor interrupt to signal the tone. Shortly after announcing the tone, the hardware containing the MET also generates a spacewire data packet containing the MET value corresponding to the tone. TIME must wait until both the tone and data packet have been received before validating the tone. The tone must have occurred approximately one second after the previous tone signal and the data packet must have been received within a specified window in time following the tone.</para><para>The hardware design choice for how the tone signal is distributed is not material to TIME configuration. The software detecting the tone need only call the cFE API function announcing the arrival of the tone. This function is designed to be called from interrupt handlers.</para><para>For detail on each of the individual configuration settings for cFE Time Services, see the following sections:</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugformsel" kindref="compound">Time Format Selection</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugfaketone" kindref="compound">Enabling Fake Tone Signal</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugtoneorder" kindref="compound">Selecting Tone and Data Ordering</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugtonewindow" kindref="compound">Specifying Tone and Data Window</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugserver" kindref="compound">Specifying Time Server/Client</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugvirtualmet" kindref="compound">Virtual MET</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugsource" kindref="compound">Specifying Time Source</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ref refid="cfetimeugsignal" kindref="compound">Specifying Time Signal</ref> <linebreak/>
 </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfetimeugparadigm" kindref="compound">Time Services Paradigm(s)</ref> <linebreak/>
 Prev: <ref refid="cfetimeugformat" kindref="compound">Time Formats</ref> <linebreak/>
 Up To: <ref refid="cfetimeovr" kindref="compound">cFE Time Services Overview</ref> </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
