<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfsmdovr" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfsmdovr</compoundname>
    <title>CFS Memory Dwell Overview</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>The Memory Dwell (MD) application enables an operator to create and control telemetry streams. These dwell telemetry streams can be defined either by table loads or by jam commands. If the operating system supports symbolic addressing, Memory Dwell supports specifying memory addresses using a symbolic name. Memory addresses to be sampled are specified in terms of a numerical &quot;offset&quot; address, and a symbolic address. See <ulink url="../mm/cfsmmugsymbols.html">Symbolic Address Arguments</ulink> in the <ulink url="../mm/index.html">Memory Manager Users Guide </ulink> for more details about symbolic addressing. Dwell stream definitions and state information (i.e. enable vs. disable) for each dwell that are provided via table load are saved across processor resets. An optional ability to insert string signatures into dwell packets is provided.</para><sect1 id="cfsmdovr_1MD">
<title>Design Overview</title>
<para>MD is a command driven, single threaded application. It will pend indefinitely on the software bus message queue until messages arrive and then processes them sequentially. Memory Dwell utilizes OSAL routines to:<linebreak/>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Read memory <linebreak/>
</para></listitem><listitem><para>Translate symbolic addresses to their numerical equivalents <linebreak/>
</para></listitem><listitem><para>Determine if a memory address is in a valid range <linebreak/>
</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para>The fastest rate at which memory values are collected by the Memory Dwell application is determined by the rate at which the <ulink url="../sch/index.html">Scheduler</ulink> issues wakeup messages. Collection rates are specified in terms of multiples of wakeup calls. Memory Dwell specifications that are initiated via Table Loads are saved to the Critical Data Store (CDS). Memory Dwell specifications that are initiated via Jam Commands are not saved to the CDS. Similarly, enabled/disabled state information for each Memory Dwell included in Table Loads is saved to the CDS. Enabled/disabled state information set by commands is not saved to the CDS.</para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfsmdopr" kindref="compound">CFS Memory Dwell Operation</ref> </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
