<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfeesugappstart" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfeesugappstart</compoundname>
    <title>Starting an Application</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>There are two ways to start an application, through the ground command <ref refid="cfe__es__msg_8h_1afe302667bda94ab954a03a4aedc17e75" kindref="member">CFE_ES_START_APP_CC</ref> or through the startup script. In either case, the object file must be loaded on board before the command is sent or before the startup script is executed. The startup script contains a list of applications and library routines to load and start immediately after the cFE finishes its startup sequence. The parameters in the command, match the elements of an entry in the startup script. See the cFE Deployment Guide for more information about starting applications by way of the startup script.</para><para>The format of the Start Application command, is defined in the structure <ref refid="struct_c_f_e___e_s___start_app_cmd__t" kindref="compound">CFE_ES_StartAppCmd_t</ref>. The members of the structure include, application name, entry point, filename, stack size, load address, exception action and priority.</para><para>If the command fails for any reason, an error event will be sent stating the reason for the failure. There may be additional information in the system log that can be viewed by sending the ES command to dump the system log.</para><para>After starting an application, the ES task sends an informational event message displaying the application name, filename of the object and the application ID. The new application will then show up in the query list downloaded in response to the <ref refid="cfe__es__msg_8h_1ada0d3b8e15c3165306e0ed914fe5acfc" kindref="member">CFE_ES_QUERY_ALL_CC</ref> command.</para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfeesugappstop" kindref="compound">Stopping an Application</ref> <linebreak/>
 Up To: <ref refid="cfeesugappsrv" kindref="compound">Application and Child Task Service</ref> </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
