<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfshkdg" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfshkdg</compoundname>
    <title>CFS Housekeeping Deployment Guide</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Follow the general guidelines below for platform deployment of the Housekeeping app.</para><para>There are two message IDs that must be included in the CFS Scheduler Table: <ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1a8a61ed97e1521ce29e32e3e80197eaf1" kindref="member">HK_SEND_HK_MID</ref> is sent out at the housekeeping request interval. The housekeeping app must send its housekeeping data to itself like any other app. <ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1af1d0c701d743a1c9dec8fbb7b9d36141" kindref="member">HK_SEND_COMBINED_PKT_MID</ref> is sent out at the desired rate for each combined packet. UP to four combined packets are available.</para><para>The HK app can build up to four combined packets based on the definitions supplied in the HK copy table. The Scheduler Table uses each telemetry IDs (<ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1abc74af0bc27c412fd15cd70c8ae0683f" kindref="member">HK_COMBINED_PKT1_MID</ref> , <ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1a6111f59066988cf233f8b81cc7725326" kindref="member">HK_COMBINED_PKT2_MID</ref> , <ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1a22ecf294ffa5232098af6c171a3366cd" kindref="member">HK_COMBINED_PKT3_MID</ref> , and <ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1ac67c88bb131ecb2caf2d0e2c84cc6b88" kindref="member">HK_COMBINED_PKT4_MID</ref> ) as a valid parameter in the <ref refid="hk__msgids_8h_1af1d0c701d743a1c9dec8fbb7b9d36141" kindref="member">HK_SEND_COMBINED_PKT_MID</ref> table entries.</para><para>The ES app uses the HK performance ID, <ref refid="hk__perfids_8h_1a26ea8526afa3f43892a04e451cb08975" kindref="member">HK_APPMAIN_PERF_ID</ref> , to keep track of the performance of the HK app.</para><para>The platform configuration file <ref refid="hk__platform__cfg_8h" kindref="compound">hk_platform_cfg.h</ref> contains parameters that can be adjusted to specific platforms. The defined parameters (and their default values) are:</para><para><ref refid="hk__platform__cfg_8h_1a9805fbcda68104a11bcfe51be34d580d" kindref="member">HK_PIPE_DEPTH</ref> defines the depth of the HK app command pipe. The default value is 40. When modifying this value, take into account not only the expected number of ground commands but the number of scheduler table entries for HK. These entries will include requests to send combined telemetry packets as well as requests to send HK housekeeping telemetry packet to itself.</para><para><ref refid="hk__platform__cfg_8h_1acba1b1ddefd87cf30a4963b0734deddf" kindref="member">HK_COPY_TABLE_ENTRIES</ref> defines the size of the HK Copy Table. The default value is 128. When modifying this value, the system engineer should consider the number of combined packets to be used as well as the number of apps whose housekeeping telemetry will be included in each combined packet.</para><para><ref refid="hk__platform__cfg_8h_1a3c07c9e0588db13388834d9636240940" kindref="member">HK_NUM_BYTES_IN_MEM_POOL</ref> defines the amount of memory dynamically allocated for the combined packets. The default value is 6144 (6KB) but must be large enough to accommodate the packet sizes as well as overhead required for the memory pool management.</para><para><ref refid="hk__platform__cfg_8h_1a09413136aac392b762c1e80aad8d7dc5" kindref="member">HK_RUNTIME_TABLE_NAME</ref> is the name of the HK Run-time table. The default value is &quot;RunTimeTable&quot;.</para><para><ref refid="hk__platform__cfg_8h_1ad363a25be94649183924265a90d69302" kindref="member">HK_COPY_TABLE_FILENAME</ref> is the name of the HK Copy Table. The default value is &quot;/cf/hk_cpy_tbl.tbl&quot;. Note that the path is specified in the filename definition.</para><para>Housekeeping app configuration parameter details are also available at <ref refid="cfshkcfg" kindref="compound">CFS Housekeeping Configuration Parameters</ref></para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfshkcmds" kindref="compound">CFS Housekeeping Commands</ref> <linebreak/>
 Prev: <ref refid="cfshkreq" kindref="compound">CFS Housekeeping Requirements</ref> </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
