<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfscsdg" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfscsdg</compoundname>
    <title>CFS Checksum Deployment Guide</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>To integrate the CS application with the cFE, follow the CFS App Integration Guide.</para><para>Follow the general guidelines below for platform deployment of the Housekeeping app.</para><para>There are two message IDs that must be included in the CFS Scheduler Table: <ref refid="cs__msgids_8h_1ab70254569caca549ac34c64be671fe85" kindref="member">CS_SEND_HK_MID</ref> is sent out at the housekeeping request interval. <ref refid="cs__msgids_8h_1a8512c92d3e153ee1ee8ba792af57c981" kindref="member">CS_BACKGROUND_CYCLE_MID</ref> is sent out at the desired rate for background checksumming.</para><para>The Checksum app generates telemetry when it receives the housekeeping request. It telemetry message ID is <ref refid="cs__msgids_8h_1abf4d664741497ddbcee7f98d89ba87b9" kindref="member">CS_HK_TLM_MID</ref>.</para><para>The ES app uses the CS performance ID, <ref refid="cs__perfids_8h_1a1cbf31b7b1740d776394abcb7bfd5ac2" kindref="member">CS_APPMAIN_PERF_ID</ref> , to keep track of the performance of the CS app.</para><para>The mission configuration file <ref refid="cs__mission__cfg_8h" kindref="compound">cs_mission_cfg.h</ref> contains mission-level parameters that can be adjusted across all platforms. The defined parameters (and their default values are:</para><para><ref refid="cs__mission__cfg_8h_1a14685855f5e163ab5ab0105a7e4ff071" kindref="member">CS_DEFAULT_ALGORITHM</ref> specifies the CRC algorithm that CS will request when calling the Executive Services CRC utility. The default value is the ES default <ref refid="cfe__mission__cfg_8h_1ae879cde370a8bb33664d990b2d5b8d17" kindref="member" external="/home/vagrant/airliner/build/reference/default/docs/html/cfe/detailed_design/cfe.tag">CFE_ES_DEFAULT_CRC</ref>. <simplesect kind="note"><para>Only the default ES CRC algorithm (16-bit CRC) is currently available in the ES CRC utility. Although other definitions (8-bit and 32-bit) exist, those algorithms have not been implemented, and setting the CS default to those values (or to other, undefined values) could lead to unpredictable results.</para></simplesect>
The platform configuration file <ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h" kindref="compound">cs_platform_cfg.h</ref> contains parameters that can be adjusted to specific platforms. The defined parameters (and their default values) are:</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a12a2d3921c7a99ee9785b64d59cbbe38" kindref="member">CS_PIPE_DEPTH</ref> defines the depth of the CS app command pipe. The default value is 12. When modifying this value, take into account not only the expected number of ground commands but the number of scheduler table entries for CS. These entries will include requests to perform background checksumming as well as requests to send its housekeeping telemetry packet to the HK app.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1ae13d12a9004374839755f0ff3b26b6fc" kindref="member">CS_MAX_NUM_EEPROM_TABLE_ENTRIES</ref> defines the maximum number of entries that can be in the table of EEPROM areas to checksum. The default value is 16.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1af810a883bf000824b5e855339fcd5f4b" kindref="member">CS_MAX_NUM_MEMORY_TABLE_ENTRIES</ref> defines the maximum number of entries that can be in the table of memory areas to checksum. The default value is 16.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a601ea903b1428909ff57b9188620632c" kindref="member">CS_MAX_NUM_TABLES_TABLE_ENTRIES</ref> defines the maximum number of entries that can be in the table of Tables to checksum. The default value is 24.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a5851a73ceabfe68587857cd45f479f2e" kindref="member">CS_MAX_NUM_APP_TABLE_ENTRIES</ref> defines the maximum number of entries that can be in the table of Applications to checksum. The default value is 24.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1ae1b017b8f16a4576d7e1f39678693d0c" kindref="member">CS_DEFAULT_BYTES_PER_CYCLE</ref> defines the number of bytes that are checksummed in a single CS cycle. The default value is 16384 (16KB). When modifying this value, be careful to keep the value low enough to avoid CPU hogging by the CS app.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1aab901627baca850a39716655cc6610db" kindref="member">CS_CHILD_TASK_PRIORITY</ref> defines the priority of child tasks created by the CS app. The default value is 200, where 1 is the highest priority and 255 is the lowest. When modifying this value, be careful to keep the value low enough to avoid CPU hogging. This value cannot have a higher priority than the CS app itself.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a63c3e0e1b006a4fee48be85d643c2c04" kindref="member">CS_CHILD_TASK_DELAY</ref> defines the number of milliseconds to delay between child task checksumming cycles. The default value is 1000 (1 second). When modifying this value, be careful to keep the value high enough to avoid CPU hogging by the child task.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1ab03e51edbe7ad32b79191a07425f01d9" kindref="member">CS_STARTUP_TIMEOUT</ref> defines the number of milliseconds the CS app must wait before entering its main loop. This is to ensure that all other apps have started up before the CS begins main loop execution. The default value is 60000 (60 seconds). When modifying this value, be careful to keep the value high enough to guarantee that all other apps have started up. Otherwise, the CS app can pend indefinitely without a timeout.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1aec7ebb6735cd2169dbe4fceeab4b249e" kindref="member">CS_DEF_EEPROM_TABLE_FILENAME</ref> is the name of the CS table defining EEPROM areas to checksum. The default value is &quot;/cf/apps/cs_eepromtbl.tbl&quot;. Note that the path is specified in the filename definition.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a709e2bcb0ae3c196ae5b5a3a9b9f433e" kindref="member">CS_DEF_MEMORY_TABLE_FILENAME</ref> is the name of the CS table defining memory areas to checksum. The default value is &quot;/cf/apps/cs_memorytbl.tbl&quot;. Note that the path is specified in the filename definition.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1ad92e34c62a0e27427eb6110d946d864e" kindref="member">CS_DEF_TABLES_TABLE_FILENAME</ref> is the name of the CS table defining table areas to checksum. The default value is &quot;/cf/apps/cs_tablestbl.tbl&quot;. Note that the path is specified in the filename definition.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1ad71cb3706c7aba6c297cf27234e636c0" kindref="member">CS_DEF_APP_TABLE_FILENAME</ref> is the name of the CS table defining application areas to checksum. The default value is &quot;/cf/apps/cs_apptbl.tbl&quot;. Note that the path is specified in the filename definition.</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a2c013c742835487def89550e7edc2c2c" kindref="member">CS_EEPROM_TBL_POWERON_STATE</ref> defines the enable/disable state of the EEPROM table at power on reset</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a8de3f880a563bfe43cbf43cab290b323" kindref="member">CS_MEMORY_TBL_POWERON_STATE</ref> defines the enable/disable state of the Memory table at power on reset</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a3611fa631ef4b23eb928ea6df817bb88" kindref="member">CS_APPS_TBL_POWERON_STATE</ref> defines the enable/disable state of the Apps table at power on reset</para><para><ref refid="cs__platform__cfg_8h_1a9fa1da5753e2ecb47743d1d02fbf91fb" kindref="member">CS_TABLES_TBL_POWERON_STATE</ref> defines the enable/disable state of the Tables table at power on reset</para><para>#CS_PRESERVE_TABLE_STATES_ON_PROCESSOR_RESET determines whether to preserve table states on processor reset</para><para>Checksum app configuration parameter details are also available at <ref refid="cfscscfg" kindref="compound">CFS Checksum Configuration Parameters</ref></para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfscscmds" kindref="compound">CFS Checksum Commands</ref> <linebreak/>
 Prev: <ref refid="cfscsreq" kindref="compound">CFS Checksum Requirements</ref> </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
