<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="cfsmmugmemtypes" kind="page">
    <compoundname>cfsmmugmemtypes</compoundname>
    <title>Memory Types</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>There are five different memory types that can be specified in MM commands. These are:</para><para>MM_RAM Generic term for RAM including DRAM, and SRAM. Memory mapped I/O that is byte addressable and requires no special code to support is accessed with this memory type.</para><para>MM_EEPROM Generic term used for non-volatile memory including EEPROM, Flash, PROM, etc. MM places no address or data alignment restrictions on this memory type. Any special alignment requirements imposed by the hardware are handled in the OSAL code for the target platform in question. MM provides commands to enable and disable EEPROM write protection via a PSP interface.</para><para>MM_MEM32 Addressable memory that must be read from and written to in 32 bit double words. Inclusion of this type is controlled by a conditional compile switch. For this memory type, MM will use the #CFE_PSP_MemRead32 and #CFE_PSP_MemWrite32 functions instead of the more generic #CFE_PSP_MemCpy. Address and data size parameters for this memory type must be 32 bit aligned or an error event will be issued and the current operation aborted.</para><para>MM_MEM16 Addressable memory that must be read from and written to in 16 bit words. Inclusion of this type is controlled by a conditional compile switch. For this memory type, MM will use the #CFE_PSP_MemRead16 and #CFE_PSP_MemWrite16 OSAL functions instead of the more generic #CFE_PSP_MemCpy. Address and data size parameters for this memory type must be 16 bit aligned or an error event will be issued and the current operation aborted.</para><para>MM_MEM8 Addressable memory that must be read from and written to in 8 bit bytes. Inclusion of this type is controlled by a conditional compile switch. For this memory type, MM will use the #CFE_PSP_MemRead8 and #CFE_PSP_MemWrite8 OSAL functions instead of the more generic #CFE_PSP_MemCpy.</para><para>Next: <ref refid="cfsmmugfileformat" kindref="compound">File Format</ref> <linebreak/>
 Up To: <ref refid="cfsmmovr" kindref="compound">CFS Memory Manager Overview</ref> </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
